A Guide to the Diploma and Certificate Collection, 1875-1972
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Diploma and Certificate Collection, 1875-1972
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-42
1 box: 2.75" x 19.5" x 25.5," 41 items
Historical Collections
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The documents were donated by various individuals. James Reed's Moral Philosphy diploma was donated by Mrs. Leslie A. Faudree. The certificates for Margaret Rust were donated by Dr. and Mrs. Delmar Weaver. Addeane Calleigh donated Guy Miller's certificate.
Scope and Content
This collection includes certificates and diplomas of various people, almost all associated with the University of Virginia. Most of the documents are from the University of Virginia but not all. The documents include diplomas and certificates for completion of medical school, nursing school, individual courses, and training courses.
Arrangement
The arrangement of the documents is alphabetical by the last name of the recipient.
Contents List
- Diploma for Paul Brandon Barringer 1877 June 28, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for a Doctor of Medicine for Paul Barringer
- Certificate for Chalmers L. Gemmill 1941 July 8, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate from the U.S. Naval Air Station to designate Chalmers Gemmill an Aviation Medical Examiner
- Diploma for Chalmers Laughlin Gemmill 1926 June 8, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from Johns Hopkins University for a Doctor of Medicine for Chalmers Gemmill
- Diploma for William T. Graham 1896 June 17, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for a Doctor of Medicine for William Graham
- Diploma for Dieter Gröschel 1958, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Cologne, Germany for Doctor medicine (magna cum laude) for Dieter Gröschel. Note that Dr. Gröschel has his own collection: Dieter Hans Max Gröschel Collection, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, Department of Historical Collections and Services, MS 54 (http://ead.lib.virginia.edu/vivaxtf/view?docId=uva-hs/viuh00054.xml).
- Certificate for Dieter H.M. Gröschel 1965 July, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate from The American Academy of Microbiology for qualification in Medical and Public Health Microbiology for Dieter H.M. Gröschel. Note that Dr. Gröschel has his own collection: Dieter Hans Max Gröschel Collection, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, Department of Historical Collections and Services, MS 54 (http://ead.lib.virginia.edu/vivaxtf/view?docId=uva-hs/viuh00054.xml).
- License for Dieter Hans Max Gröschel 1965 July 1, 1 license (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  License from the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Department of State for the practice of Medicine and Surgery in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania for Dieter Hans Max Gröschel. Note that Dr. Gröschel has his own collection: Dieter Hans Max Gröschel Collection, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, Department of Historical Collections and Services, MS 54 (http://ead.lib.virginia.edu/vivaxtf/view?docId=uva-hs/viuh00054.xml).
- Certificate for Dieter Hans Max Gröschel 1969 September 18, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate from the Commonwealth of Massachusetts Board of Registration for registration as a qualified physician for Dieter Hans Max Gröschel. Note that Dr. Gröschel has his own collection: Dieter Hans Max Gröschel Collection, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, Department of Historical Collections and Services, MS 54 (http://ead.lib.virginia.edu/vivaxtf/view?docId=uva-hs/viuh00054.xml).
- Diploma for Washington B. Grove 1895 June 12, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in Biology (Histology and Bacteriology) for Washington Grove
- Diploma for Washington B. Grove 1895 June 12, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in Physiology for Washington Grove
- Diploma for Washington B. Grove 1895 June 12, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in Anatomy for Washington Grove
- Diploma for Washington B. Grove 1896 June 17, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for a Doctor of Medicine for Washington Grove
- Diploma for B. Randolph Kennon 1892 June 29, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in Physiology for B. Randolph Kennon
- Diploma for B. Randolph Kennon 1892 June 29, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in Medical Jurisprudence for B. Randolph Kennon
- Diploma for B. Randolph Kennon 1892 June 29, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in chemistry for B. Randolph Kennon
- Diploma for B. Randolph Kennon 1892 June 29, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in Anatomy for B. Randolph Kennon
- Diploma for B. Randolph Kennon 1892 September 21, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the M.D. Course in Materia Medica for B. Randolph Kennon
- Certificate for William P. Mark 1971, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for membership in Alpha Omega Alpha at the University of Virginia for William Mark
- Certificate for Guy Miller 1899 June 30, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for Guy Miller, M.D. for attending the course of Clinical Lectures on all branches of Medicine and Surgery from May 8th to June 20th, 1899, at the San Francisco Polyclinic Post Graduate Medical Department of the University of California. It is signed by Leo Newmark, M.D. and Henry Krentzmann. Donated by Addeane Calleigh on January 5, 2015.
- Diploma for James Clayton Reed 1868 July 2, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  This is a diploma from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the School of Moral Philosophy for James Reed. James was a brother of Walter Reed. The diploma was given to the UVa medical library by Mrs. Leslie A. Faudree, a great niece of James Clayton Reed and the wife of Lesie A. Faudree, M.D., Class of 1939, UVA School of Medicine.
- Certificate for James Clayton Reed 1868 July 2, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  This is a certificate from the University of Virginia for being Proficient in the Class of Political Economy for James Reed. James was a brother of Walter Reed. This certificate is rolled and loose in the box, not in a Mylar cover.
- Diploma for Catherine Marie Russell 1951 June 11, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma from the University of Virginia for a Doctor of Philosophy in Biology for Catherine Russell
- Certificate for Catherine Marie Russell 1962 July, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate from the American Board of Medical Microbiology for qualification in Medical and Public Health Microbiology to Catherine Russell
- Certificate for Margaret Ora Rust 1919 June 12, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for Margaret Rust for completing three year course in the University of Virginia Hospital School of Nursing (Donated by Dr. and Mrs. Delmar Weaver)
- Certificate for Margaret Ora Rust 1903 May 14, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate from the Nurses Examining Board for the State of Virginia for Margaret Rust for meeting requirements for being a registered nurse (Donated by Dr. and Mrs. Delmar Weaver)
- Diploma for Charles Slaughter 1877, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for Charles Slaughter, M.D. of Lynchburg, Virginia. Certificate is for private instruction in Physical Diagnosis by Prof. Alfred L. Loomis. Reads "... has been a member of my class in Physical Diagnosis and has pursued the study of the same in the Wards of Bellevue Hospital in the year A.D. One thousand eight hundred and seventy vii, I hereby confer this certificate." It is signed by Alfred Lebbeus Loomis, Professor of Practice of Medicine and Pathology Medical Department, University of the City of New York. This was formerly artifacts01039 and was donated by C. Marshall Lee, Jr., Slaughter's grandson, and accessioned in 2000.
- Diploma for Charles Steele 1875 July 1, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in the School of Latin
- Diploma for Charles Steele 1875 July 1, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in French Language and Literature
- Diploma for Charles Steele 1876 June 29, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in German Language and Literature
- Diploma for Charles Steele 1876 June 29, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in School of Greek
- Diploma for Charles Steele 1876 June 29, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in School of Pure Mathematics
- Certificate of Proficiency for Charles Steele 1877 June 28, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being proficient in Literature and Rhetoric
- Diploma for Charles Steele 1877 June 28, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in School of General Chemistry
- Diploma for Charles Steele 1877 June 28, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Charles Steele from the University of Virginia for being a Graduate in School of Moral Philosophy
- Diploma for Ermoye Avise Stoll 1948 June 14, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Diploma for Ermoye Stoll from the University of Virginia for a Bachelor of Science in Nursing Education
- Certificate for Oscar Swineford 1926, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for Oscar Swineford from Alpha Omega Alpha declaring his membership
- Certificate for Oscar Swineford [1972], 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate is for Oscar Swineford from the American Association of Certified Allergists for serving as President from 1971 to 1972
- Certificate for Oscar Swineford 1943 June 11, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate is for Oscar Swineford from the American Board of Internal Medicine for being certified to practice Internal Medicine, Allergy
- Certificate for Virginia Lassiter Williams September 30, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate is for Virginia Lassiter Williams from the University of Virginia Hospital School of Nursing to certify completion of a three year course.
- Certificate for Emma Garnett Wood 1903 June 17, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for Emma Wood for completing a two year course in the University of Virginia Hospital School of Nursing (Wood was in the first graduating class of only three)
- Certificate for Fletcher D. Woodward 1923 April 1, 1 certificate (Box-folder 01 [oversize])
  Certificate for Fletcher Woodward from the Board of Directors of the Manhattan Eye, Ear and Throat Hospital for serving one year as an Assistant and House Surgeon in the Eye Department